I am a spirit created by smokeless fire,
a genie.
We were created on Thursday,
the day after the angels.
If you hear what I am saying now
in your native language,
that's because I am a genie.
Genie, turn off the alarm.
With our supernatural strength
and mystical powers,
we genies grew more arrogant,
even aspiring to surpass him.
But I had no interest in any of that.
Becoming greater than him
would be such a hassle, no?
Despite this, he,
in his rage, sent his angels,
ordering them to decimate
the haughty genies.
After 300 years,
when the long battle came to an end…
so did the lives of all genies
except a few, including myself.
I took refuge in a lamp.
Once the world was purified,
on the very next day, a Friday,
he created another species to replace us.
Out of clay, he made you.
Humans.
And then he commanded all
to bow their heads
to the first human he created.
All angels and surviving genies
bowed their heads,
but I refused to do so.
APRIL 5TH
FLYING OUT
I, who was created from smokeless fire,
could not bow my head to a human
molded from mere clay.
Enraged, he threw me out of heaven.
Fallen to hell,
I made just one request.
I would agree to my fate on one condition.
That I be allowed to tempt humans
and drag them down to hell.
I vowed to prove to him
just how pathetic
his precious humans truly were.
He granted my request
but named a condition of his own.
Did you get that?
I shall grant your request.
But if you happen to meet
even one pure human soul,
you will be cast
to a depth greater than hell…
What's it rambling on about
all on its own?
Maybe it's broken.
That is the origin story
of the three wishes
that you humans know of.
After that, I left hell to inhabit vessels
such as lamps, rings, or jars…
granting three wishes
to any human who summoned me.
Humans are selfish and lazy.
They are insatiable
and quick to betray those closest to them.
They kept sinking deeper into corruption,
and I was vindicated.
I had been
right all along.
But you.
You, from a small land in the East.
Even while taking your final breath,
you used your three wishes for others.
It just could not be.
Little girl.
Little girl made of clay.
You frail, dying human.
I shall observe your death,
and I shall take a handful of dirt
that is, in part, your flesh and bones.
Because of you, my lamp might end up
buried deeper than darkness itself.
But even so,
I will not bow my head to you,
a lowly being made of mere clay.
I shall remember your gaze
and the smell of your clay.
And, if a new master appears
and summons me,
when I am able to be
a part of this world once more,
I will scour the world
and find you again.
I shall do whatever it takes
to corrupt you
and kill you.
Remember this.
I will seek you out, and my name…
is Iblis.
GENIE, MAKE A WISH
One Gogung set meal.
Right away, ma'am.
Stop it.
Stop coming.
I saw you every year.
I knew it was you.
The same table, the same day.
Every year, for ten years.
You've done enough.
Did you think I wouldn't know?
Of course you should know.
That's why Auntie's been leaving cash
and taking my photos for over ten years.
Right?
Mom.
She said not to worry about money.
- Just take care of Ka-young--
- Take care of her? How?
What does she expect me to do?
So she doesn't seek out her mom.
Goodness!
That wretched bitch!
Should I tell Ka-young her mom's dead?
And she calls herself a mother?
Goodness, she was just a little girl.
What mother abandons her child
for being difficult?
That's when Grandma
started growing chilies.
And so, every year,
the chili field grew, grew--
- I don't want to know.
- Grew…
I don't want to hear it.
- What is it you want to--
- Please don't cut me off.
After 20 years, you're finally hearing
your youngest daughter's voice.
It grew, grew, and grew.
It's much wider now.
The chili field.
How did you find out where we live?
Are you quizzing me?
Bet you're happy to have ID.
Yes, I'm stoked.
RESIDENT REGISTRATION
CERTIFIED COPIES, EXTRACTIONS
A copy of my residence record, please.
You must be Ka-young.
What brings you here?
I checked the register.
This building that you manage, Auntie,
appears to belong to my mom.
Where are they now?
My dead mom, dad,
eldest sister, and second sister?
One Gogung set meal.
What do you do for your hands to be…
You know better than I do
why I abandoned you.
I've sent you plenty of money.
This? I bought it
with my hard-earned money.
All the money you sent me
was donated long ago.
These hands?
So you didn't even ask your sister
what I do for a living.
It's work where I get scratched,
cut, and burned every day.
Don't I sound just like a murderous bitch?
Grandma told me
that people should always be kind.
I know that face too.
A face of fear.
You learned to be kind?
You say you know what fear is?
If so, would I have left you?
You never even tried to teach me!
The thing is, ma'am,
in Ka-young's case,
trying to teach her won't work.
How can that be?
Why say that without even trying?
Even if the whole world says
it's impossible, I won't give up on her.
Please just tell me about her classes.
What did my Ka-young do to the frog?
Did she not do the dissection correctly?
No. She actually did it perfectly.
Then why did you ask to see me?
That class was two months ago in spring.
But Ka-young was still
pleading with me today.
She's been begging to dissect frogs again.
She wants to do it all the time
and asks why we don't do it more.
She's asked every single day since.
That hurts.
You hurt me!
The frog's hurting too.
But the frog can't even tell you that!
Damn it!
I can't breathe!
Neither can I.
Let me go!
I'll kill you, Grandma!
I'm gonna kill you!
You let go first.
I'll let go if you let go.
That hurt! I'm going to kill you!
I'll kill you, Grandma!
When you hug someone,
I will also hug you.
If you cut someone with a knife,
I will also cut you with a knife.
And if you kill someone,
I will kill you too.
These are our rules. Do you understand?
Let go of me!
You're hurting me!
Learn through the pain.
Learn until you're out of breath.
If you can't seem to learn, memorize.
Ka-young.
Look closely at my face.
This is
despair.
If you see Grandma making this face again,
it means
that you and I will both die. Am I clear?
I missed it!
Do it again! Your face of despair!
I've already forgotten about the despair.
This is hope.
The face of hope.
So, after that,
I stopped doing those things
because those were our rules.
But living like that
means life is just no fun.
I'm so bored, Mom.
- What on earth are--
- I told you not to cut me off.
I was always curious.
On TV, people in this situation
cry their eyes out.
I wondered if I'd cry.
Whether you would cry.
I was just curious, you know.
But here we are, both dry-eyed.
Grandma sometimes cries in secret.
I assume
it's because of me.
But you know, Mom,
if Grandma ever cries
because of you again…
my hands will be wringing your neck.
Until you are no longer able
to make any face at all.
Until the very end.
I came to say this
in case you ever did talk to me.
Since you spoke to me this time…
I won't be back.
Bye, Mom.
THIS IS DUBI-DUBAI TOURS
PLEASE BRING AN EXTRA LAYER
My goodness, what a view!
"Dubai."
Listen up, everyone.
Can you all see
that sand whirl over there?
In Arabic culture, they refer to
that phenomenon as a "waltzing genie."
No way, a genie?
You mean the lamp spirit we all know?
How incredible!
But it looks like a sandstorm is coming.
Are you all okay to continue the tour?
You underestimate Koreans.
You all have your masks, don't you?
- Let's go.
- Sure.
Okay, you've got an hour of free time.
- Feel free to keep taking photos.
- Okay.
The waltz is a partner dance,
but they're doing it solo? What a loser.
You're right. They're a total loser.
My gosh, you're right.
Goodness, dear. You're a hoot!
Wow, honestly, you're--
Where's your hotel?
Oh boy, look at the genie!
Mom, wait for me.
Waltz!
How's the desert tour?
CHOI MIN-JI
Vast, hot, and windy.
Perfect for burying a family of four.
Stop that! Ticktock, ticktock.
Why are you getting in my way?
Why do you keep interfering?
What the hell did I do
to put that damn look of fear on you?
You didn't even try to make an excuse.
And why is your skin so perfect?
You've had it
easy…
all along.
The Gogung set meal tastes like crap.
It's a damn rip-off!
I just threw it behind me…
Who was that?
Who's messing with me, damn it?
Wow! The genie is dancing the waltz!
Amazing. It looks incredible!
Move, and I'll stab you.
Your hair is…
Who are you? Why did you follow me?
I said I'd stab you.
So it is you.
The smell of that clay.
The same lump of clay
that imprisoned me.
It's been 983 years.
You almost got me.
What's with this almighty idiot?
WHAT'S WITH THIS ALMIGHTY IDIOT?
"What's with this almighty idiot?"
There is only one Almighty. I'm a spirit.
Listen carefully, little girl.
My name
is Iblis.
I was created from a smokeless fire…
Why'd you shake my lamp like that?
People know me as a Jinn
or Genie…
You shook it too hard.
Hey, stop there.
My lamp.
I told you to stop for a moment.
I know you're her!
I'm Genie.
I'm the one and only Genie,
spirit of the lamp!
It's actually this long, but I usually
wear it nice and short like earlier.
Damn.
I'll admit this is pretty impressive.
How did you get in here?
I'm pretty sure
I told you in a loud voice earlier.
I am the lamp spirit, Genie.
I can inhabit whatever I want,
"Kki Kka-young."
You have perfect pronunciation,
but butcher my name?
It appears that you don't quite grasp
the situation, so listen carefully.
I don't listen to what others say.
Only my grandma.
Consider these your grandma's words.
I'm here against her wishes.
Piss off!
You're contradicting yourself!
Do you seriously not remember me?
From 983 years ago.
Nothing rings a bell?
If you're talking about 983 years ago,
that'd be the Goryeo era.
Choi Soo-jong founded a country
and went on about something-jong
and this or that king, then Goryeo fell.
How would I remember that?
Is that how far back we go?
Yes, that's how far back we go!
Look at my hair, will you?
Come on, don't you see how long it is?
I see it.
So your hair grew that long
over 983 years,
but your beard hasn't grown an inch?
Of course,
that's a perfectly valid question.
But I don't really have an explanation,
and I'd rather move on,
so can you just cooperate?
Do you know what it took for me
to stay in that lamp for 983 years?
I'll bite.
What did it take?
The dignity I was born with.
Goryeo.
Where the hell is Goryeo?
I'm going to destroy it
as soon as I get out!
The thing is, Master,
the land called "Goryeo"
no longer exists as it was overthrown
by someone called "Yi Seong-gye."
They also believe
in the cycle of death and rebirth.
Something "carnage," was it?
Reincarnation.
So they are reincarnated.
Sade, head to that country this instant.
Go there and search every inch of it
with a fine-toothed comb.
Check if that lump of clay was reborn.
Hey, excuse me?
Right, look here. Can I…
Excuse me? Might you have
seen this girl?
I'm not sure. I don't think
I've seen her around these parts.
I upheld my dignity,
even up to the 600-year mark.
Though I guess
I did wear the lamp out a bit.
Just let me out already, will you?
Why do I only have one piece of furniture?
It's way too short for me!
I know you're listening.
Hello?
FUCK
F U
Seriously?
Darn lump of clay.
I'm coming for you.
Just wait till I'm out!
Master, something called
an automobile has been invented!
These wheeled things
walk around on their own now!
I'm telling you so you don't freak out
or start gawking when you get out.
Sade came by now and then
to inform me of the changing world.
And when I visited the East, I acquired
the face of someone from that region.
I like it so much
that I've been wearing it ever since!
I'm not sure why,
but the lady of the house
keeps giving me heaps of rice…
That was around the 800-year mark,
and I was ready to blow a fuse.
Think about it.
I sent countless humans to hell.
Out of all those humans,
only one had a pure soul.
So why is it all on me?
Does no one else find this odd?
Going through all that
made me miss you so much. Truly!
I hoped you would be reborn
and that, even once,
you would find yourself dreaming
of meeting a spirit like me.
I hoped you'd have
a lot of friends and a lot of family
so I'd have
a ton of opportunities to ruin you.
And then,
when the 900th year rolled around,
I finally prayed.
"Please, I beg for just one more…"
Asleep, it seems.
Dozing off on a genie?
What did you hear before your dreams?
The 700-year part when I was midstream?
Would starting over be too extreme?
Darn it.
What the hell does it say?
It says you shouldn't shake it.
That an ill-tempered genie
might get angry.
Well, you made a great first impression.
Dare I say, affable?
Well, how kind of you.
So you were awake?
I just woke up
because it got so interesting.
Or I woke up, and it got interesting.
So what happened after you prayed?
Did you receive an answer?
I did.
Dear Iblis,
I will grant your request.
But if the day comes
when you bow before my creations again,
you shall be beheaded.
What did you pray for?
"Please, I beg for just one more…"
and then?
Chance.
Please, I beg for
just one more
chance.
If the new master who releases me
is another of your cherished creations,
if they are a truly righteous human,
then I will banish myself
to hell forevermore.
But if I do manage to corrupt them, then…
let me be a free genie!
Grant me the eternal freedom to move
between heaven and hell as I please.
Sure, you might wonder
how that's any different from now,
but the devil's in the details, you know?
Okay?
And at long last,
I realized that a new master had appeared.
But after all that, it's you again?
I figured it was a good thing.
But who knew you'd act like this?
How have I been acting?
Right now,
you don't respect or fear me at all.
You're a mere lump of clay.
So I'm gonna prove it for good.
What a failure his creations truly are.
The extent to which
humans can be corrupted.
You're saying this to my face?
Over breakfast?
So what is it that you want from me?
Have we not discussed that yet?
Oh, that's right.
What I want is three of your wishes.
Not one, not two, but three whole wishes.
The rules are simple.
No bringing back the dead.
No traveling to the future.
Anything besides that,
your wish
is my command.
A face of seduction.
Slick words.
That's right.
Come forth, into corruption.
You're an evil bastard.
Wait, what? You figured that out already?
Well, you're right, I guess.
Evil since before Christ.
Piss off right now.
Or should my first wish be for you to die?
Easy now.
It's confusing
that you were born like this.
Was the version of you 983 years ago
just full of it?
Perhaps you weren't righteous,
just inarticulate.
I was righteous?
Me?
Master!
The girl was finally reincarnated!
But a war broke out,
and she died a hero,
fighting alongside a certain admiral!
Right.
His name was Yi Sun-sin!
I've found the girl again, Master,
but she's dead this time too.
Apparently, she was helping someone
this time too. Who was it again?
Of course!
I hear he was called An Jung-geun!
You were like that for three lives,
but I guess this one's different.
Pulling a knife at the drop of a hat?
Now that's a habit I can get behind.
Okay, let's properly corrupt you
in this lifetime.
At its core,
pleasure is needed for corruption.
Master, I shall bestow the world's
greatest pleasures upon you today.
Bring me a camel!
I've already called an Uber.
What's an "Uber"?
We don't ride camels anymore.
We ride Ubers.
Right. And what is this "Uber"?
Why should I tell you?
Why do we keep talking in circles?
No, wait.
It's great that you're so rude.
Uber? Sure.
983 years is a long time,
and in that time,
the world must have changed a lot.
No wonder I'm out of the loop.
I just need to remain calm.
Sade the brat!
Why didn't he tell me
about those two-wheeled things?
It almost got me!
It did get you.
What is that?
Why is it making that sound?
Yes, Grandma?
Right now? I'm going to go sightseeing.
All right, good.
You're keeping up with your meds, right?
All right, attagirl.
Don't eat too many cold foods,
and steer clear of any boys
who try to chat you up.
Don't look twice,
even if he calls you pretty.
And if a guy says he'll do things for you,
put him on the phone right away.
You got that?
- She wants me to put you on.
- Put what on?
No way. This face is set to be attractive
to anyone in the world…
What's she saying?
I swear I heard a man's voice.
Hello?
Ka-young?
Hello…
Hello?
The only reason I didn't kill
is because of my grandma's rules.
I got it out of my system in other ways.
They say nothing beats fatigue.
Beat?
Oh, right. Beats fatigue… Fatigue, right.
Yes. Every day from the age of eight
until I went to college,
I would plant sesame with my grandma
and then harvest it. Same with chilies.
A FAMILY-ORIENTED PSYCHOPATH
My entire body would ache,
but I had to memorize poems
and stay at the top of my class.
Every day, I was so exploited for labor
that even if I thought,
"I want to kill something,"
it would soon be morning.
HIGH-FUNCTIONING PSYCHOPATH
SETTING A GOOD EXAMPLE
I see. Man, I'm getting chills.
You're so funny, ma'am.
NO, IT'S NOT FUNNY
You're older than me.
Sorry?
You started farming two months ago?
Yes.
Do you have a car?
Come by if you have an accident.
First service gets 10% off.
Ma'am-- I mean, Ka-young?
Whatever. You're totally scary
yet super funny.
By the way, I'm just so curious.
Do psychopaths really not feel love?
You know, being ready
to give your life for someone else.
I would be willing
to kill for someone else.
Doesn't that count as love?
VIDEO UPLOADING
Wow, how beautiful!
Mom, I want to buy everything here!
Right?
Wow, how beautiful.
Tour guide, I want to buy everything here.
Sorry, why are you telling me that?
Make your three wishes.
Do it now. Right here. This instant.
Get lost. Find yourself a barber.
Is that a wish?
Do you want to get slashed for real?
Hey, why would you say such a thing?
What do you mean…
My gosh. Look at these lamps.
My gosh. Look…
You know it's rude to come back
from overseas empty-handed, right?
What is Dubai's most popular souvenir?
Chanel, of course.
Right. Thank you.
Where's the department store?
I was only joking.
I was joking too.
Right, you were joking, weren't you?
That was too funny.
They're all right here. Magic lamps.
Goodness. Do you think
a genie will appear if I rub this?
Make your three wishes.
Do it now. Right here. This instant.
I told you to piss off.
You've picked the wrong person.
I have rules and routines.
Those two things keep my life going.
So I don't have any wishes to begin with.
May I ask
who you're talking to?
Genie. This bastard has been
talking to me nonstop since yesterday.
- Sheesh, she's so strange.
- Don't make eye contact.
Right, only you can see me.
One of my magical powers.
You piece of shit.
You beardless son of a bitch
with your stupid long hair.
You just won't shut up! For fuck's sake!
I told you to piss off!
Why am I the only one to see you?
I look like a lunatic!
You're already corrupt.
Very corrupt.
All right, let's step it up a notch!
Hey, you're back.
So damn salty!
This is driving me nuts.
Try and get rid of me again.
I can't leave your side. You're my master.
I'm considering other options.
Are you the only genie?
No. I'm the most famous genie.
Why do you ask?
Damn it.
What the hell?
Do all genies look the same?
Do you know a genie with long hair?
I do. And I suppose you're looking
for that genie's weakness,
or his flaws,
or perhaps a way to eliminate him.
So you intend
to fight a genie with a genie?
It's a new angle. I'll give you that.
But, unfortunately,
he is the only genie
among us brothers who grants wishes.
If you've seen him, you'll know.
He can inhabit any space in the world
and is perfect from head to toe.
The walking definition of dignity.
Weaknesses?
None. Flaws? I'd love to give him one.
But eliminating him is quite simple.
I'm sure you've figured it out.
If you make your three wishes…
Hey, on your left.
You dare deceive me?
That actually hurts. And what,
have you been all righteous and dignified?
You've rubbed every lamp you could find.
He knows The Art of War?
That's not in my favor.
If things aren't going your way,
start by changing the subject.
You put your hair up. How pretty.
It's a pain to lug around.
And it's so obvious that you're lying.
If the conversation gets awkward,
just lean into it.
Never mind the beard business.
How are we communicating?
How do you know Korean?
I don't speak Korean.
I'm speaking Arabic right now.
But wherever I go,
I sound fluent
because I'm the lamp spirit, Genie.
Make it sound like Arabic.
What did you say?
You're Korean, aren't you?
You don't know Arabic.
I'm not Korean or a person.
How much is this? Where is the toilet?
No cilantro, please.
- Happy?
- Sounds like basic Arabic.
I'm a native speaker.
Even your basic Arabic sounds rough.
It's all in your head.
Have you always been so violent?
If so, I'll get my hopes up.
Is your grandma well? Why no wishes?
Do you really not remember me?
And he knows how to deflect.
Enough of that.
Do you know how to fly?
When you watch shows with vampires,
they just fly off, all the way to…
Move out of the way, crazy!
Are you trying to get killed?
He's singing my praises.
"Can I fly?"
Did that answer your question?
Who'd you say earlier? Vam… who?
Wow.
So you really are a genie.
I'm now going to scream with happiness.
I know how this goes.
Go ahead!
Wait, why are you smiling like that?
You smile differently from other humans.
This is real joy.
Joy?
So you finally have a wish?
No.
I finally have an opportunity.
The perfect location.
The perfect adversary.
From this height,
would his skull crack first?
No telling my grandma.
Who exactly is your grandmother?
That was way too quick.
Man, you startled me.
Your timing was completely unexpected.
"Man, you startled me"?
Most people panic while pushing someone,
but you're only just startled?
I should have been slower to get mad.
Your arm broke first? Not your skull?
Depends on how many times you spin
and whether it's a clean drop
or if you hit a building.
I hit a building,
so I came up a little sooner.
I smashed my head and back
but pieced myself together on the way up.
I see.
But I know that face.
Real
rage.
If you knew, why do it?
Don't you agree, Master?
I accept
whatever punishment.
So please,
make sure we are punished.
You and I both.
I hoped you'd be different,
but not this different.
What exactly are you?
Beg.
Beg for your life.
Tell me it's your first wish.
Wish it.
Seeing this,
I can tell those wishes
won't do me any good.
How smart of you.
You're right. Once you've made
all three wishes, and I'm no longer bound,
I'm going to kill you.
If that's your plan,
why not just scrap the wishes
and throw me off right now?
I'm having
an absolute blast right now!
Subtitle translation by: Jimin Choi